Hi I'm Jamie and welcome to Teachers Tech! Today
I want to show you how to use Adobe Acrobat more
specifically how to use Adobe Acrobat Pro.
I find this software gets overlooked a lot
with organizations people have licenses to
this software or maybe they have other Adobe
and this is part of the package and they're
not taking advantage of how powerful this
is with this program and this is just going to
be a beginner's tutorial here today so I'm not
going to cover everything but I'm going to cover
the things that I think that you'll want to know
to get using it right away and that is how do
you create a PDF document from here how do you
edit a PDF document in here it's great you can
take a picture of a document that you take and
bring it in and you can edit the text edit the
images to it you can reorganize the pages you
can delete pages combine PDFs and then when you
need to sign something add an e-signature to it
really quickly and have it saved for the next
time you need to sign a PDF all these things I
want to cover with today on how to use Adobe
be Acrobat Pro let's get started with this
you do need to be logged in to your account to use
Adobe Acrobat Pro and if you look up top you can
see I am logged in I'm just going to go to click
on this and you can see where I can sign out if I
wasn't there I could sign in with my credentials
and it would ask if I was part of whether it be
a individual or part of an organization on it so
you do have to be signed in have that account now
I just want to start with this right here this
create and edit and this is what we're going to
be walking through most of these here today and
this forms and signatures down here if I scroll
down you can see there's more that can be done in
here but I'm just going to focus on kind of those
beginning things that I mentioned in the intro
here now if I go over up top you can see that
there's different tabs if I click on home this is
where you're going to see recent files that you've
worked on you're going to see items that's shared
by you shared with others because you can share
with others these documents and I just want to
I'll point that out as I open up a document to
show you where that feature is also but I want to
start with something really cool here today and
I'm just going to go to tools here and I'm going
to start with create a PDF and I'm just going to
start this from an image so this is just going
to be a JPEG and when you go ahead and start a
start a brand new PDF I could either open a PDF
but if I don't have one to start with I need to
grab something to start it with and I have lots of
different options so I could grab it from a Word
document I could grab it from an Excel document a
text file and there's more you can see right here
there's check more check more formats and you
can see all the different ones you can upload
so I'm just going to go ahead and select this and
I have some examples I want to use today now this
is just an image of an old certificate and you're
probably wondering why I'd be using this but I'm
going to go ahead and just hit create on this and
you're going to see it load it into the PDF here
this is what's certificate it's just an image
of it but what I really want to show you is how
well you can work this works Adobe Acrobat Pro
to edit something like this so all I'm going to
do is go to the tool the edit PDF right here so
I'm going to click on this and it goes through
performing the page kind of looking through it
it's recognized the language in English and I'm
just going to close out of here because what I
want to point out now this is editable what I mean
is if I go to where it says 350 if I just click in
here now on this one you can see I could go ahead
and delete this just like that I've deleted it I
could go back and add a different number if I say
250 so I'm editing this picture because I brought
it in and started my PDF from here I could delete
different things also so if I wanted this whole
uh this line gone I could just hit delete on my
keyboard and it's gone because I had everything
selected so I can start making these changes to
it really really quickly quickly later on in this
tutorial I'm going to show you how you can edit
how you can add more text add more images but I
just wanted to show you this really quickly and
even something like this I could change the
date here let's go to 31 I could resize this
here to make sure that this fits so you can grab
your handle I can move it around so I can get my
handle and start moving things around sometimes
when you're working with a document like this it
doesn't always come out perfect so I just want to
point that out like it's September if I was trying
to move it you can see it it's a little bit off on
it but I'm going to go Ctrl Z to go back one step
and if I was done making format changes to this I
could go ahead and just save this now and I could
go file save it save as and give it a name and I
could save it back to where I want to do it or I
could convert this so it looked out here I could
convert this to a Microsoft Word document I have
all these options I can convert it to a picture at
the end whether it be a JPEG Tiff PNG so there's
all these different ways but save your documents
and you're going to notice that we're going to get
different tabs up top here okay I want to show
you one more thing with pictures that I just
took off my phone and one I took as a picture and
one I scanned in just to show you the difference
I'm going to go back to my tools up top here I'm
going to again go create PDF I'm going to select
a file and this one right here so I'm just going
to open this up this is just a document lying
around on my floor I picked it up took a picture
of it and I'm just going to go create and you'll
be able to see it was kind of kind of crinkled and
everything and here it has some images on it so if
I go back in and hit edit PDF remember this just
started as a JPEG but now it is a PDF you can see
up top on the tab when I started it it did turn
it into a PDF but I'm going to go to edit PDF it
runs through the page recognition and after that's
done it usually doesn't take very long depends on
how big the document is it's straightened it up
a little bit but now again I can go through and
start clicking in here and making edits so if I
wanted this to be different I could go in here
and just as simple as that starting deleting
things here I could take the picture and hit
delete notice when I take the hit delete on the
picture it leaves the it's like it's cut out and
it has the white background I'm going to show you
when I bring in the scan that I did from my phone
just using notes on my phone how it's a little
bit different but I I just wanted to point out
how easy just take a picture and start these PDFs
with the jpeg or something like that and then you
can even add more PDFs to it add more images
and get it larger and larger okay let's go over
and I'm going to open up a file for you I have
another file that I'm going to open up it's just
in my desktop right here I do want to point out
notice that there's a close up here if you want
to close out of a tool just say close it doesn't
close it from up top it just brings you back to
all the different tools okay so I'm going to go
ahead and open this file up and I'm going to open
this PDF up here so this is the same image same
one but I scanned this one on my phone just using
notes on my iPhone and I saved it as a PDF sent it
over so I just have to open it up and it opens up
automatically because it's already a PDF I find it
works a little bit better if you scan it as a PDF
rather than image so just so you know if you have
that choice to choose a PDF now I'm going to go
over to my edit PDF I want to point out there's a
number of different places you can get to it even
if I click here it's going to bring it to the same
thing so when I click this it performs the page
recognition goes through and just like before
it finds everything in here where I can start
leading text if I want I can even take to go
over to the pictures I could size these just
by grabbing the handles I can move them around it
gives an idea of how easy and how quickly and how
well this works when you start modifying any of
these here now remember if you made your changes
to save it so that if you don't forget if you put
a lot of hours into it now what I want to point
out here too again I can close out of this and it
goes back to just the all my tools again I'm going
to open up another file and this is where I want
to show you how you can edit the text or add more
so I'm going to go to my Adobe practice files
here and this time I'm going to just grab this
one right here and it's just some random text in
here and it has some images also this is a longer
document than the other one so I want to change
it show you how you can change your views first
if I go up to view notice I have page display
here so I can go to two page view here if I'd
like to do that so in something like this I like
to choose I'd go to multiple pages I can see the
page numbers on here I have 12 pages but do take
a look at your different uh your different view
options here yeah with your navigation and your
page view you have your zoom up top as well I
just wanted to point those out now if I go I'm on
the this is going to be the first page right here
so I am going to go back to my just by one page
here so we can see it and I'm going to zoom up
here like this okay so like I showed you before we
can edit our PDF it will run through this so this
is 12 Pages it runs through this pretty quickly
and now I can start editing like I showed you
in that first one this is a little easier should
everything should be captured quite well you can
type whatever changes you want through here I can
make changes also so just like any format adding
if I look over on the right where my formatting
is I can choose a different font if I'd like to go
through you can see all the different options that
are there I can change the font size making all
these adjustments here like normal formatting to
it you can now this is edit so when I click edit
that means I'm editing what's there already if I
want to add text I can go ahead and hit add text
what this does it allows me to put a box in so if
I just draw a box here I can now type whatever I
want into that box and do the same formatting
that I did before so if you need to add text
that's new and it's not edited just add text this
way now I'm going to move along and I want to add
an image so if I go down and I'm going to just
scroll I have an empty spot right here because
I want to put the image somewhere that has room to
go I can add an image I can go ahead add image and
I'm just going to grab the image here of this
one that I already showed you to be very very
beginning I know it doesn't make much sense but
it's just an image it's attached to my mouse and
if I click it goes in I can move it around too
if I want I get the handles I can size just like
I showed you before so we can move it around size
and as soon as I have an image in here I want to
point out that we have the objects all lit up here
because now I can start doing things over here do
I want to flip it vertically do I want to flip
it horizontally do I want to crop it so if I go
to head head and crop it I can start cropping it
down to making it look better depending on how I
want and I'll just do a quick few crops and you
get all these different options I could rotate
it if we get those different options and I can
even replace the image so if I was going to go
oh I want a different image now if I click on
it I could go grab a different image and it'll
be replaced in there and we do have some other
options over here with bring to front send back
bring forward depending on what layer or how you
want it inside here now I do want to point out
I'm going to go to my view display here to my two
and I'm going to go so this has documents in it
everything I showed you before if I was under edit
and now if I click a picture I get all the objects
in here also so I can resize it at this point I
could crop it from here as well so if I wanted
to start cropping I could do all those things same
things with the images in here I replace it to a
different one so it's it's quite easy to work with
inside of here okay what else can you do to edit
this well you could add links so let me show you
I'm going to go up to the first page again and I'm
just going to zoom up into my single page and I'll
zoom up again and let's say I wanted to add a link
what I can do is hit link and I have some options
here now edit web or document link I'm just going
to go over this one if it had links in here I I
could Auto create web links from the URL if they
were in here I could remove all the web links in
here so you see the different options I'm going to
add a link and let's say if it was this word right
here I wanted where the link to be I would draw it
over top and it comes up with what do I want well
it's a visible rectangle I get some options how I
want it to look color line style line thickness
what do I want to have happen well let's say I
open a web page so I'm going to leave it at that
one and you could use it to go to other pages in
the document as well I'm going to hit next and
enter in the URL so if I go ahead enter in the
URL let's say I put my note my own in there I hit
OK and you might think well it's not working it's
not working well it's not going to work until you
hit close out of the edit and then now what you
can do is notice that it's a hyperlink if I click
on it it's just saying that it's going to be you
know if I trust this site allow and it's going
to go to that website so you can hide these too
remember you don't have to show the lines on it
too so pretty easy to add some links to it okay
I'm going to go back to edit here and I still want
to show you a few other things we can add a header
or footer if it doesn't already have one you can
see if we drop down we can add through here I'm
not going to go through these steps but I do want
to show you how easy it is to add a watermark so
in this document if I wanted a watermark I could
go add and now I could type what I want so if I
just it's just going to be draft I can choose
my color all these formatting options uh maybe
I want this to have some rotation on it I can
have the opacity a little bit down so a little
bit see-through and hit OK you can see I can also
apply to most multiple files and hit OK and we get
this draft that's going to be on all the pages so
if I change my view here I'm going to drop down up
here this time and you can see that we have some
options to fit one page at a time up there there
and draft is going to be on all of them here
so those are just some editing features inside
Adobe Acrobat Acrobat Pro that are quick to use
and you can make a lot of great changes on this
now I want to show you a little bit more with
some of the features that you can do with this
another feature that I use a lot is the organizing
the pages and combining files and you can kind of
do both uh within the organized Pages here so I'm
going to start here actually so I'm just going to
click on organize Pages here and it shows me the
view of everything now what I really like what I
can do with this I can change the page order
by simply grabbing you can see now if I click
and hold I can change it to a different spot if I
resave it this is where it will be if I don't want
a page if I click on it I have the delete option
and it warns me in my short I'll hit okay so I can
change the order I can then I can delete if I want
and it's that simple to start making those changes
I could have one selected I could extract so if
there's one page I want so delete pages after
extracting extract Pages as separate files so I
can go ahead and extract depending on what options
that I want I and if you take a look you have have
different options up top here if I go replace this
is where I could go grab a different PDF and
replace the one that I have here before now if
I go insert I can put another PDF in here so let's
go insert and I could be coming from a clip from
clipboard if I copy paste it I can come from a web
page a blank page I'm just going to go from file
here as an example and I'm going to go grab that
one that I scanned earlier of the weights and I'm
going to hit open and where do I want this located
I'm just going to leave it after this selection
right here you can see if I want it at the first
or last page but I'm going to leave it here so
there we go we have this page that I brought in I
combined the file and again I can drag it around
change the order of it very quickly if I want
to go to my other view close out of this tool
so then what's the difference with combined files
well combine files if I go to combine files I can
go ahead and open multiple items and look combine
them so if I go to add files and go to here maybe
I want this one and I'm just going to hold down
con shift on a couple of these and select multiple
ones so I'm I'm picking uh let's pick these
ones right here so I'm going to pick this one
this one and this one here and hit open and I
get all three of these here that you can see
I have some options I'm not going to go through
these here but I'm just going to hit combine and
what you'll see is it combines all of them so
again if I go over to my organized Pages it's
put all of them together in them so if I look at
my tabs up Top This is called a binder three so
when I've combined them that's what they're that's
the default you can change the name on it here was
the other one that I was working on before with it
with the ones I was combining in here doing that
way so a couple different ways to change the order
Pages combine files but Adobe Acrobat Pro makes it
very easy to perform this function so I do want to
point out the export PDF here so if I hit export
this is where again and I showed you the other
way at the beginning the files save as where you
can choose do you want this as a Microsoft Word
document spreadsheet PowerPoint image you have all
these other ones and then you can just go ahead
and hit export depending on what you want I'm
just going to hit close and the other thing I want
to point out is up here so we can share a link of
this file so if I was going to share the link with
somebody else if we're using the Adobe Cloud with
this I could share the link I could send file by
email and I can also share this file with others
so if I click on this I would be putting the name
or emails in here and I can add comments or turn
this on to loud comments and I can actually add
a deadline as well so you would need to be in
the cloud sharing this with others that have the
account also okay so those are just a couple of
quick things I wanted to point out before we got
to an another feature that I use a lot in Adobe
Acrobat Pro in that is the fill and sign right
here so I don't want to fill inside this one I
have a different document for that so I'm going
to go ahead and open that document up right away
I'm going to go and open up this sample form and
I'm going to go over to the fill and sign when
I click on the fill and sign look at the icons
up top here I get different ones where I could
add text so if I have this selected I just need to
click somewhere and I could add text very quickly
and I can go ahead and delete it or change the
size after but this is already a form that has
some components to it that I can just click so
since I'm in fill inside I can click this in and
the check mark goes right in I do have check marks
up here too I could just click and add check marks
or an X if I wanted to do any of those as well
in a different tutorial I'm going to show you
how you can make these fillable forms in Adobe
Acrobat Pro uh and because then you can have it
so people can just fill out their information
so like here is already a spot for their name
where I could go ahead and type it like so and go
fill this all out but I'm not going to do that in
this tutorial what I want to point is how do you
create your signature your e-signature in Adobe
Acrobat Pro I'm going to go up to sign here so if
I click sign I can go and add a signature so what
I'm going to do is just click add and now at this
point at First Option it just picks it as typing
I can change my style very quickly if I wanted
to just use something like that another option
I could go to draw and I could go and try to spell
my name with my mouse like that and another option
would be an image so maybe you take a image of
your name on a nice crisp white sheet of paper
and you have a good contrast to the dark pen so
I'm going to grab this one here this is just a
PNG file of my signature and I'm going to use
this one and hit apply so now I you can see it's
attached to my mouse if I click where I want it
it just goes there I can resize this if I would
like very simply by grabbing it I can delete it
also now anytime I come back to any form I need
to sign in the fill and sign I go up and I can
just click this again it's there so if I click
it again you can see how I can add it anywhere
so this is a great feature to have usually when
people send me documents to say now I'm just using
Adobe Acrobat Pro my signature is all already
there you can create a digital signature with a
certificate with it too I'll do a different uh
different tutorial on that as well now I'm going
to keep moving on here across the top because you
can actually request e-signatures too so what
I could do with this document I could send it
to somebody and request in a spot that they sign
it also so that's a great feature to have within
here and then if you follow along here if I hit
next you can see I can save this as a read-only
copy save your file as a read only copy and no one
can modify or request e-signature so then at this
point I can just hit continue and then I can I I
just save it like so and so that's another great
feature so the features that I'm showing you today
are the ones that I use most so I'm editing PDF
lots I'm combining PDFs I'm taking images bringing
in and creating a PDF and I use the e-signature a
lot now there's a lot more that Adobe Acrobat Pro
can do for you I will have future tutorials on
this I just wanted to get you playing with this
with some features that I thought you might be
wanting to use right away let me know what you're
looking for with this program or others thanks
for watching this time on teachers Tech I'll see
you next time with more Tech tips and tutorials